Guide to the Merrill G. Burlingame Papers 1880-1990
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
- General correspondences, 4
  - Lew and Marian (Box 28, Folder 73)
  - Liberty, Margot (Box 28, Folder 74)
  - Lloyd, Carol (Box 28, Folder 75)
  - Lolomi Lodge (Box 28, Folder 76)
  - Lubick, George (Box 28, Folder 77)
  - MacGilvra, E.E. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - McKerrow, Glenn (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - McNamara/Marlow Ranch (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Malin, James C. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Malouf, Dr. Carling (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Mansfield, Mike (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Martin, Fred J. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Metcalf, Senator Lee (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Miller, Don (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Miller, Gertrude Haight (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Milne, Jim (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Miracle, Ralph (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Misevic, George (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Monroe, Bessie (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Moyhes, Stacy (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Mueller, George and Oscar (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Napoli, Sandi (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Norton Clan (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Nowels, Mrs. Ed L. (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Omber, Lavern (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - O'Neill, Thomas (Tip) (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Ortenburger, Leigh (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Osgood, Ernest S. (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Ovitt, Mable (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Palladin, Vivian (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Parker, Lois (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Payne, Joseph P. (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Peterson, J.H./Peterson, Helen (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Place, Marian (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Prewitt, Nancy C. (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Publishers (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Rankin, J. Lee (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Rankin Memorial Service (Box 29, Folder 34)
  - Reiner, Ralph (Box 29, Folder 35)
  - Renne, R.R. (Box 29, Folder 36)
  - Rickards, Colin (Box 29, Folder 37)
  - Rickey, Don (Box 29, Folder 37A)
  - Rocky Mountain College (Box 29, Folder 38)
  - Safford, Jeff and Rydell, R. (Box 29, Folder 39)
  - Sampson, June (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - Sargent Family (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - Schoenberg, Father Wilfred (Box 29, Folder 42)
  - Schwinden, Governor Ted (Box 29, Folder 43)
  - Smith, Helen H. (Box 29, Folder 44)
  - Smith, Scott (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Spencer, Amy (Box 29, Folder 46)
  - Thiessen, N.E. (Box 29, Folder 47)
  - Thrapp, Dan L. (Box 29, Folder 48)
  - Tretsven, Wayne (Box 29, Folder 49)
  - University of Iowa (Box 29, Folder 50)
  - Valentine, Louise (Box 29, Folder 51)
  - Van Horn, Otto and Kittie (Box 29, Folder 52)
  - Wear-Ever Company (Box 29, Folder 53)
  - Wellington, Duke (Box 29, Folder 54)
  - Wellington, Duke (Box 29, Folder 55)
  - Wellington, Duke (Box 29, Folder 56)
  - Whealdon, Bon (Box 29, Folder 57)
  - White, M. Catherine (Box 29, Folder 58)
  - White, Dudley (Box 29, Folder 59)
  - Willson, Fred S. (Box 29, Folder 60)
- Montana Place Names, 5
  Primarily research notes and summary forms documenting a comprehensive list of Montana place names created or collected by Burlingame. Material explaining the origin of the particular name is included in some files along with pertinent correspondence from interested individuals.
  - Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Decisions on Geographic Names in Montana (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Formations of Counties, Reservations and Political Divisions in Montana (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Indian Origin (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Maps (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Montana Historic Markers (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - "Montana Names" Scott Daniel, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - "Montana Place Names" - Federal Writers' Project (WPA) (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - "The Origin of Some Montana Place Names" - Montana Writers' Project Mabel C., 1940 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - "How the State of Montana Was Named" (various photocopies) (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - "The Origin of Some Montana Place Names" J.P. Rowe (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Place Names, general (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Absaroka Mountain Range (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Beaverhead County (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Beaverhead County-Bannack (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Big Horn County (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Big Horn County-Fort C.F. Smith (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Big Horn County-Fort Custer (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Big Horn County-Yellowtail Dam (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Blaine County (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Broadwater County (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Central Montana (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Carbon County (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Carter County (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Cascade County (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Cascade County-Fort Shaw (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Chouteau County (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Chouteau County-Fort Benton (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Chouteau County-Fort McKenzie (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Cooke City Highway (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Custer County (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Custer County-Fort Keogh (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Daniels County (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Dawson County (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Deer Lodge County (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Fallon County (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Fergus County (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Fergus County-Camp Cook, Fort Clagett (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Fergus County-Fort Maginnis (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Fergus County-Judith Landing Historic District (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Flathead County (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Forts in Montana (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Gallatin County (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Gallatin County (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Gallatin County (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Gallatin National Forest (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Garfield County (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Glacier County (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Golden Valley County (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Granite County (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - "The High Line" Carl M. Gunderson (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Hill County (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Jefferson County (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Judith Basin County (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Lake County (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Lewis and Clark County (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Lewis and Clark County-Last Chance Gulch* (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Liberty County (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Lincoln County (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Madison County (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Madison County-Beaverhead Rock (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Madison County History* (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Madison County-Red Bluff (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - McCone County (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Meagher County* (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Mineral County (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Missoula County (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Missouri River (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Musselshell County (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Northeast Montana (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Notes (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Park County (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Park County (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Petroleum County (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Phillips County (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Pondera County (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Powder River County (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Powell County (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Prairie County (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Ravalli County (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Richland County (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Rivers (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Roosevelt County (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Rosebud County (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Sanders County (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Sheridan County (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Silver Bow County (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Stillwater County (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Sweet Grass County (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Sweetgrass Hills (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Teton County (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Toole County (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Treasure County (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Valley County (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Western boundary-Montana (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Western Montana (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Wheatland County (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Wibaux County (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Yellowstone County (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Yellowstone County-Pompeys Pillar (Box 35, Folder 22)
- Indians, 6
  Notes, correspondence, photocopies and original documents pertaining to Native American tribes. Montana groups predominate, but some of the files are of a general nature. Some of the files were created while Burlingame conducted research for court cases involving the Crow, Salish, Kutenai, Blackfeet and Gros Ventre tribes during the 1950s and early 1960s.
  - Activities, Drafts, Culture (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - "American Indian Contribution to Civilization" Everett E. Edwards; Americanizing the White Man Felix S. Cohen (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Assimilation (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Assiniboine (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Battles (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Blackfeet (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Blackfeet/Blackfoot? letter from John Ewers (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Blackfeet-Student Papers (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Blackfeet-Canadian-U.S. (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Blackfeet-Canadian Claims Case (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Blackfeet-History (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Blackfeet-Influences on Congress (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Blackfeet-Livestock (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Blackfeet-Minerals (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Blackfeet-Opening of reservation, 1888-1889 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Blackfeet-Railroad Influence (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Blackfeet-Social customs (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Blackfeet-Claims (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Blackfeet-Stevens Treaty, 1855 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Blackfeet-Wades-in-the-water, Julia (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Bureau of Indian Affairs annual report, 1940 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - "George Catlin's Creed about American Indians" (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Cheyenne Tales (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Citizenship (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Confederated Salish-Kutenai Tribes (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Cree (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Cree publications (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Crow/Blackfeet battle, 1834 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Crow-Claims case (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Crow-Claims case (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Crow-Claims case (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Crow-Claims case (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Crow-Fair (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Crow-History (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Crow-Student papers (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Crow-Water rights/Yellowtail Dam (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Disabled reservation Indians (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Diseases (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Education (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Ethnogeographical Guide (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Flathead (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Flathead (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Flathead (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Flathead (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Flathead-Salish-Kutenai Historical Report Draft (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Flathead-Salish-Kutenai Historical Report Draft (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Flathead-Salish-Kutenai Historical Report Draft (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Flathead-Salish-Kutenai Historical Report Letters (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Fort Belknap (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Fort Peck Council handbook (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Fort Peck Indian Reservation - correspondence, notes (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Gambling/Liquor (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Garraghan's Indian collection (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - "The Indian Tests the Mainstream" D'Arcy McNickle (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - "The Indians Among Us" Verne Dusenberry (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Indians At Work (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Indians of Montana/Plains student papers (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Indians of Montana/Plains student papers (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Interagency Task Force report (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Kalispel Tribe (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Kutenai/Kutenai notes (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Kutenai/Kutenai notes Claims (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Kutenai/Kutenai Contract with Merrill G. Burlingame (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Kutenai/Kutenai Correspondence (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Kutenai/Kutenai Historical report (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Kutenai/Kutenai History (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Kutenai History (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Forts and Flathead posts (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Legislation (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Little Shell/Turtle Mountain Chippewa of Hill 57 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts-Great Falls Chancery (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Metis (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Missions (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - "Montana Indian Affairs" C.S. Kenyon (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - National Defense (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Nez Perce (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Northern Cheyenne (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - "The Old Milk River Indian Agency" (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Poison on the Indian Frontier (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Prehistoric Indian Settlements of the Yellowstone Valley (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Relationship with the federal government reading list (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Reservations (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Riel, Louis (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Rocky Boy Reservation/Cree (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Rocky Mountain College (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - "The Salish of Montana" Don Scott (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Shaker Cult (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Sioux (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Societies and fraternities (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Superintendents and agents (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Tipis and lodges (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Trails (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - "Trail of Broken Treaties" (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Treaties-National Archive sources (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Tribes (Montana) (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - Warriors in Transition by John G. Langan (Box 40, Folder 31)
- Montana State College/Montana State University, 7
  Notes, correspondence, photocopies, and original documents pertaining to the history of MSU and selected administrators, faculty, and staff. Much of this material was gathered by Burlingame while preparing his book, History of Montana State University (1961) and The Montana Cooperative Extension Service: a History, 1893-1974 (1984). Classroom lecture notes and syllabi for courses taught by Burlingame are also included. Original manuscripts created or collected by Harriett Cushman have been placed in this series as well.
  - Alumni Greeting (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Alumnus-John O. Bye (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Annual faculty report, 1966/1967 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Athearn, Lt. Col. George P. (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Blue and gold award (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Board of higher education (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Brewer, Helen R. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Brewer, W.R. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Business, School of (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Campus ministry (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Carillon (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Chalkey, Gladys B. (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Civil engineering (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Consolidation (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Communist seminar (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Contributions to the State (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Cushman, Harriette (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Cushman, Harriette--personal papers (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Cushman, Harriette--Christmas cards (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Cushman, Harriette--Estate (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Cushman, Harriette--Genealogy (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Danforth Chapel (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Danforth Chapel (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Danforth Chapel (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Danforth Chapel (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Danforth Chapel (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Danforth Chapel (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Dusenberry, Verne (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Emery, S.M. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - English, speech, theater arts department (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Enrollment map, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Epsilon Sigma Phi (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Faculty (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Fairway Farms (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Fairway Farms (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - 50th anniversary, 1943 April 17 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - 50th anniversary-Brief (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - 50th anniversary-Preliminary sketch (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - 50th anniversary-notes (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Finances - 1968 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Flag (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Founders Day, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Graduate list, 1896-1912 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Hamilton, J.M. (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Hannon, Olga Ross (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Hill foundation (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Historical sketches, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - History of MSC and Montana Experiment Station, 1923 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - History 300 notes (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - History 300 notes (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - History 300 notes (Box 43, Folder 17-18)
  - History 302 notes (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - History 302 syllabi (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - History department (Brewer award) (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - History department history and annual reports (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - History department, 1893-1968 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - History and philosophy (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Home Economics department (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Home Economics department (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Home Economics Department (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Home Economics department (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Honorary degrees (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Index reference cards (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Indian center (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Indian Club (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Johnson, Leon (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Horsfore, Tom and Kranzel, Carl (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Kermer, John (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Land grant institutions (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Land records (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Lorentz, Floyd (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Maiden, B.F. (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript lists (Montana State University) (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - McDonald, Rita (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - McDonald, Rita (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - McDonald, Rita (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - McGill Museum (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - McKee, Thomas (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Montana agriculture experiment station (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Montana Extension Service History-contributions (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Bell, E (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Montana Extension Service History-third draft (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Bell, E (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Cooley, F.S. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Cushman, Harriet (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Mercer, Ralph (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Jacobson, N.N (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Montana Extension Service History-notes (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Montana Extension Service History-notes (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Montana Extension Service History-4 H (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Home Demonstration (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Home Demonstration (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Poultry (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Starch, Elmer (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Starch, Elmer (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Bell letters (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Starch, Elmer (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Starch, Elmer-Tape transcripts (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Starch, Elmer-Tape transcripts (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Montana Extension Service History-The Taylor Years (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Starch, Elmer, response to "The Taylor Years," transcript from tape recording, complete version, 1970 (Box 47, Folder 10B)
  - Montana Extension Service History-The Taylor Years (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Montana Extension Service History-revisions (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Montana Extension Service History-revisions, 1972 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Montana Extension Service History-revisions, 1973 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Montana Extension Service History-revisions, no date (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Montana Extension Service History-revisions, Aashheim (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Montana Extension Service History-revisions, chapters 2-9 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Montana Extension Service History-revisions, chapters 9-10 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Montana Extension Service History-Starch, last changes (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Montana Extension Service History-revisions, chapters 7-9, galley (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Montana Extension Service History-revisions, summary, Bell and Burlingame (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Montana Extension Service History-revisions, Tootell and Beers (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Montana Extension Service History-final draft (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Montana Extension Service History-final draft (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Montana state board of education (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - "Montana State University and the small high school in Montana" (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - "The Montanan" Bea McKenna (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters-non newspaper (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Notes and clippings (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Peck, Lucy Stafford (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Pirsig, Robert (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Phi Kappa Phi (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Philosophy department (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Pi Kappa Alpha (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Pi Kappa Alpha (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Pi Kappa Alpha (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Poultry (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Religious Emphasis Week (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Renne, Roland R. (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Rhodes Scholars (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Second Century Campaign (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Special Collections (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Sigma Chi (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Sloan, William F. (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - 75th Anniversary (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Speeches (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - State board of education (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Strand, A.L. (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Strand, Mollie (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Student charts (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Student housing association (proposed) (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Summer quarter notes, 1967 July 5 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Taylor, Bob (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Textbook ban, 1968 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - University chancellorship, 1943 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - "Women's Day Activities (1904-1908)" Edna Tracy White (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Warrants, 1932 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Wilson, M.L. (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Wilson, M.L. - Fairway Farms (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Wilson, M.L. - Symposium (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - "Women's responses…." James, David (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Women's activities, 1904-1908 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Women's day speaker: Opal Petrarsh Daff (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Wright, Freeman (Box 51, Folder 9)
- Organizations, 8
  Notes, correspondence, photocopies and original documents pertaining to various organizations of which Burlingame was a member or was interested in as a research topic. Most organizations are Montana related and include the Christian Church, the Montana Historical Society, the Masonic fraternity, and the Museum of the Rockies.
  - American Indian Institute (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Christian Church (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Christian Church (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Christian Church (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Christian Church (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Christian Church-speeches (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Christian Church-speeches (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Christian Church-Montana (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Christian Church-Montana (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Christian Church-Montana (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Christian Church-Montana (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Bozeman trail association (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Gallatin County Historical Society (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Gallatin County Historical Society (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Heckler's Club (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Heckler's Club (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Heckler's Club (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Labor (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Masonic Lodge-"Gallatin Masonic Light" (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Masonic lodge #18 Centennial (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Masonic lodge #18 centennial (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Masonry, Montana (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - McGill museum (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Montana Committee for the Humanities (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Montana Ghost Town Preservation Society (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Military organizations in Montana (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Montana Archaeological Society (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Montana Bicentennial Committee (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Montana Historical Society (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Montana Historical Society (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Montana Historical Society, 1968-1969 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Montana Historical Society, 1970 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Montana Historical Society, 1970 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Montana Historical Society, 1970-1971 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Montana Historical Society, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Montana Historical Society, 1972 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Montana Historical Society, 1972 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Montana Historical Society, 1972 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Montana Historical Society-Burlingame interview transcript (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Montana Institute of the Arts (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Montana Museums (Box 56, Folder 5)